Guide to the Undergraduate Publications Board Reference Collection, 1893-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Undergraduate Publications Board Reference collection 1893-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
0.5 linear feet Extent: 300 Items
UA.01.11.0040
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Publications Board Reference Collection was compiled from various sources by University Archives staff for reference and research.
Historical Note
taken from Undergraduate Publications Board homepage http://www.duke-union.org/About_UPB?
Since 1924, the Undergraduate Publications Board, commonly referred to as the Pub Board or UPB, has overseen the production of each of the university's recognized publications (with the exception of The Chronicle and Towerview). The Board also approves and supports emerging publications, known as Independents, runs the Blackburn Literary Festival, and administers the John Spencer Bassett Fund. Its continuing mission is to provide diverse forums in which students can engage their creative, intellectual, political and literary faculties.
Currently (2007), the UPB oversees the production of eleven publications: The Archive; Blind Spot; Carpe Noctem; The Chanticleer; Duke Blue; Erudito; Latent Image; Matter Magazine; Vertices; Passport Magazine; and Woman's Handbook. A sampling of other titles produced during the UPB's history include: Tobacco Road; Prometheus Black; Missing Link, Jabberwocky; and Teacher-Course Evaluation Book.
Collection Overview
The Undergraduate Publications Board Reference Collection includes a list of Pub Board publications (past and present) a general history of the organization, as well as clippings, histories, lists of editors, flyers, and other materials relating to individual publications. Folders are also present for the Bassett Fund and the Blackburn Literary Festival. The Bassett Fund finances public lectures, defrays honoraria for the Blackburn Literary Festival, and supplements new undergraduate publications. The Blackburn Literary Festival honors the spirit of sharing and love of literature embodied by Professor William Blackburn.
Subject Headings
College prose, American -- North Carolina -- Durham; Duke University. Undergraduate Publications Board; Durham, N.C., Duke University Publications Board
Related Material
Undergraduate Publications Board records, 1911-1997.
University Archives. Duke University.
The Chronicle, 1905-ongoing
Duke Univeristy Archives, Duke University.
Detailed Description of Collection
- Container List, 1 Box
  - List of publications (Box 1)
  - General History, 1922; 1935; 1976-1979 (Box 1)
  - Bassett Fund (Box 1)
  - Blackburn Literary Festival, 1979-1996 (Box 1)
  - Clippings (Box 1)
  - Publications (Box 1)
    - Archive, 1893-2005, bulk 1970-1982 (Box 1)
    - Blindspot, 1991 (Box 1)
    - The Blue Devil's Advocate, 1987/88-1989/90 (Box 1)
    - Carpe Noctem, 1994-1998 (Box 1)
    - Chanticleer, 1977-1985 (Box 1)
    - The Chronicle (Box 1)
    - Duke Blue, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
    - Duke and Duchess [magazine], 1938, 1950-1951 (Box 1)
    - The Duke Guide (Box 1)
    - Duke Humanities Review (Box 1)
    - Duke Review (Box 1)
    - Eruditio (Box 1)
    - Jabberwocky, 1980, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Latent Image, 1977-1978, 1993, undated (Box 1)
    - Missing Link, 1983-1987 (Box 1)
    - Tobacco Road, 1978-1983 (Box 1)
    - Vertices, 1994 (Box 1)